This whole process of embryonic flexion, not
Tout  ce  processus  de  flexion  de  l 'embryon,  non
only organizes the placement of my joints,
seulement  organise  la  mise  en  place  de  mes  articulations,
but also begins to cause a phase of embryonic delimitation.
mais commence aussi à provoquer une phase de délimitation de l'embryon.
A set of four embryonic structures.
Un ensemble de quatre structures embryonnaires.
There are four embryonic structures.
Il y a quatre structures embryonnaires.
These four structures are the septum transversum, the
Ces  quatre  structures  sont  le  septum  transversum,  les
pleural membranes,
membranes  pleuraux,
peritoneal, the
péritonéale, le
paraxial mesoblast of the
mésoblaste paraxial de la
trunk wall and the
paroi du tronc et le
esophageal mesenchyme.
mésenchyme oesophagique.
Beyond the prechordal
Au-delà de la plaque
plate, in the cephalic
précordale, dans la zone
region, the mesenchymal
céphalique, les cellules
cells of the embryonic disc
mésenchymateuses du disque embryonnaire
will become the pericardium
deviendront le péricarte
and the septum transversum.
et le septum transversal.
This is the notochord.
Ça, c'est la notocorde.
Parachordal means
Paracordale, ça veut dire
next to.
à côté.
Prechordal,
Précordale,
that means there and beyond the prechordal plate, that is, here, in
Ça  veut  dire  là  et  au -delà  de  la  plaque  précordale,  c 'est -à -dire  ici,  dans
the cephalic region, the mesenchymal cells, the
la  zone  céphalique,  les  cellules  mésenchymateuses,  les
mesenchymal cells, which are there, of the
cellules  du  mésenchym,  qui  sont  là,  du
embryonic disc, will become
disque  embryonnaire,  deviendront
the pericardium and the septum transversum.
le  péricarte  et  le  septum  transversal.
In other words,
En d'autres mots,
Not only is your heart already developing above your head,
Non seulement votre cœur se développe déjà au-dessus de votre tête,
but how can we explain that?
mais comment pouvons-nous expliquer ça ?
By the fact that it makes that movement.
Par le fait que ça fait ce mouvement-là.
That is, they are already in place, in fact.
C'est-à-dire qu'ils sont déjà en bonne place, en fait.
They are already there.
Ils sont déjà là.
And this is very important because it's something that,
Et ça, c'est très important parce que c'est quelque chose que,
in classical embryology, we don't see it.
dans l'embryologie classique, on ne le voit pas.
We describe the movement of the heart, you see?
On décrit le mouvement du cœur, tu vois ?
It descends, but no, it doesn't descend, it's the other one that goes up, you see
Il  fait  une  descente,  mais  non  il  ne  fait  pas  de  descente,  c 'est  l 'autre  qui  monte,  tu  vois
?
?
Same thing with the kidneys, we describe the ascent of the joint, but no, the kidney stays
Même  chose  au  niveau  des  reins,  on  décrit  l 'ascension  du  joint,  mais  non,  le  rein  il  reste
in place, it's the rest that descends.
en  place,  c 'est  le  reste  qui  descend.
When I hear that sentence, it immediately clicks, it means that the pericardium and
Moi  quand  j 'ai  cette  phrase  tout  de  suite  ça  me  fait  tilt,  ça  veut  dire  que  le  péricard  et
your diaphragm are a functional unit,
Ihr Zwerchfell ist eine funktionelle Einheit,
and we will see that when we study the heart, we will see that the rhythmicity,
und wir werden sehen, dass, wenn wir das Herz studieren, wir sehen werden, dass die Rhythmik,
of the heart is supported by the pericardial fascia. In other words, if I remove
des Herzens, die durch die Perikardfaszie gestützt wird. Mit anderen Worten, wenn ich
that the electricity
dass die Elektrizität
alone of the heart is not enough to maintain it and that there is a closed oscillation system,
allein des Herzens nicht ausreicht, um es aufrechtzuerhalten, und dass es ein Schwingungssystem gibt,
almost like
geschlossen, fast wie
a rather brilliant energy, which occurs in the pericardium to support the
eine ziemlich geniale Energie, die im Perikard erzeugt wird, um das Herz
heart in its rhythmicity.
in seiner Rhythmik zu unterstützen.
And moreover, it is completely connected between the heart
Und außerdem ist es vollständig zwischen Herz
and the diaphragm.
und Zwerchfell verbunden.
They are not two separate things, they are initially almost the same cells that will organize themselves.
Das sind keine zwei getrennten Dinge, es sind ursprünglich fast dieselben Zellen, die sich organisieren werden.
We see that it is found up there, then it does that, that's
Wir sehen, dass es sich dort oben wiederfindet, und dann macht es das, es
how they are integrated here,
ist so, wie sie hier integriert sind,
both at the level of the pericardium which is here, and
sowohl auf der Ebene des Perikards, das hier ist, als auch
the septum transversum which is there.
des Septum transversum, das dort ist.
So the flexion, the notochord causes a
Die Beugung, die Chorda dorsalis, führt also zu einer
specific movement at the level of my neural tube which in turn will cause a
spezifischen Bewegung auf der Ebene meines Neuralrohrs, die wiederum eine
neural groove movement which organizes the
Bewegung der Neuralrinne hervorruft, die die
lateral structure into small vessels that become a nutritional
seitliche Struktur in kleine Gefäße organisiert, die eine
supply but a relative brake on growth due to the very important
nährende Versorgung, aber auch eine relative Wachstumsbremse durch die sehr
development of my neural tube.
wichtige Entwicklung meines Neuralrohrs darstellen.
the ectoderm around that rolls up and in this rolling movement,
das Ektoderm, das sich darum herumwickelt, und in dieser Wickelbewegung
we're already going to imagine that the cells are there, you see, here.
werden wir uns bereits vorstellen, dass die Zellen dort sind, siehst du, hier.
Well, they come to do that, so it doesn't move, it does that.
Nun, sie kommen, um das zu tun, also bewegt es sich nicht, es macht das.
And that's how these mesenchymal cells come to integrate
Und so integrieren sich diese mesenchymalen Zellen,
to form the future pericardial tissue and form the diaphragmatic anlage.
um das zukünftige Perikardgewebe zu bilden und die Zwerchfellanlage zu formen.
It brings cells that will develop around.
Das bringt Zellen hervor, die sich darum herum entwickeln werden.
All this grows and at some point, my visit...
All dies wächst, und irgendwann ist mein Besuch...
The vitelline pedicle no longer grows. It has finished its job.
Der Dotterstiel wächst nicht mehr. Er hat seine Arbeit getan.
It's just a small remnant that inserts with vitelline vessels
Es ist nur ein kleiner Rest, der sich mit Dottergefäßen
around what we call the umbilical region with the umbilical networks.
um das, was wir den Nabelgrund nennen, mit den Nabelgefäßen einfügt.
The vesicle will be integrated into the pedicle to form the umbilical cord
Die Blase wird in den Stiel integriert, um die Nabelschnur zu bilden,
and the pericardium will integrate with the septum transversum to form this tissue
und das Perikard wird sich mit dem Septum transversum integrieren, um dieses Gewebe zu bilden,
whose origin is initially beyond the prechordal plate.
dessen Ursprung ursprünglich jenseits der Prächordalplatte liegt.
We see here the septum transversum, you see, which is here, which
Wir sehen hier das Septum transversum, siehst du, das hier ist, das
is an important tissue.
ein wichtiges Gewebe ist.
We will see that there is growth.
Wir werden sehen, dass es ein Wachstum gibt.
Initially, the septum transversum is there, you see, at the fourth
Am Anfang ist das Septum transversum dort, siehst du, in der vierten
week.
Woche.
Then at the fifth week, it horizontalizes, you
Dann, in der fünften Woche, horizontalisiert es sich, du
see, and then it starts to descend, here, like that.
sieht, und dann fängt es an, hier so herunterzukommen.
But in fact, look, it comes here, and then it descends completely.
Aber eigentlich, schauen Sie, es kommt hierher und sinkt dann komplett ab.
like that. So, what does that mean? Initially, it has its origin
so. Was bedeutet das? Ursprünglich hat es seinen Ursprung,
when it is
wenn es
2 mm, it originates at the very high cervical vertebrae. C3,
2 mm ist, nimmt es seinen Ursprung im Bereich der sehr hohen Halswirbelsäule. C3,
C4, which is the origin
C4, was der Ursprung
of the phrenic nerve. And then, it
genau des Nervus phrenicus ist. Und dann
ends up at the lumbar level,
findet es sich schließlich im Lendenbereich wieder,
by pulling here. What is this drawing in
indem es hier mitzieht. Was ist diese Zeichnung in
biodynamics?
der Biodynamik?
is wrong. Why?
ist falsch. Warum?
Because it makes it descend, whereas it's...
Weil es herunterzieht, während es...
It's the rest that comes. Exactly. This is the image of the
Es ist der Rest, der kommt. Genau. Das ist das Bild des
train leaving. I think I'm moving, but in fact, I haven't moved.
abfahrenden Zuges. Ich glaube, ich bewege mich, aber eigentlich habe ich mich nicht bewegt.
The truth is that this becomes a fulcrum
Die Wahrheit ist, dass dies zu einem Stützpunkt wird
and it's all the rest around that has dislocated.
und der ganze Rest darum herum hat sich aufgelöst.
Do you understand the idea?
Verstehen Sie die Idee?
So the diaphragm, it settles, it positions itself, and I have enormous growth
Also, das Zwerchfell installiert sich, positioniert sich, und ich habe ein enormes Wachstum
around,
drumherum,
and it is this growth of the posterior part, you see here, 1, then
und es ist dieses Wachstum des hinteren Teils, du siehst hier, 1, dann
the growth, 2, the embryo actually grows, you see,
das Wachstum, 2, der Embryo wächst tatsächlich, du siehst,
and it creates a, in fact it will even create an absorption space here, as
und das schafft einen, tatsächlich wird es sogar einen Absorptionsraum hier schaffen, da
it grows, it will create a space here, you see, between there, and there I have a space
es wächst, wird es hier einen Raum schaffen, du siehst, zwischen dort, und dort habe ich einen Raum,
that opens here.
der sich hier öffnet.
And what will be attracted there, into that space?
Und was wird dorthin, in diesen Raum, gezogen werden?
My lungs, which are a suction field as we will discuss,
Meine Lungen, die ein Saugfeld sind, wie wir besprechen werden,
which will be aspirated here, here, which we will see in phase 2, at the
die hier, hier, angesaugt werden, was wir in Phase 2, am
viscerocranium.
Viszerokranium, sehen werden.
The diaphragmatic origin is found very, very high,
Der Zwerchfellursprung befindet sich sehr, sehr hoch,
it is found at the level of the second and third cervical vertebrae.
er befindet sich auf Höhe des zweiten und dritten Halswirbels.
But it's all the part above.
Aber es ist der ganze obere Teil,
that grows. So the nerve
der wächst. Also der Nerv
is not pulled like that,
wird nicht so gezogen,
but it's almost pulled like that.
sondern er wird fast so gezogen.
We see this setup
Wir sehen diese Entstehung
of this diaphragm
dieses Zwerchfells
linked with
verbunden mit
this excessive growth
diesem übermäßigen Wachstum,
that we will see, that we will study tomorrow
das wir sehen werden, das wir morgen
in detail, why the embryo
im Detail studieren werden, warum der Embryo
at some point, it stops
ir hält irgendwann an
in its flexion.
in seiner Beugung.
The embryo straightens up. Why
Der Embryo richtet sich auf. Warum
does it straighten up? What happens?
richtet er sich auf? Was passiert da?
It's a question of fluids on the sclerotome.
Es ist eine Frage der Flüssigkeiten auf dem Sklerotom.
with the straightening of the telencephalon.
mit der Aufrichtung des Telencephalons.
The ascent of my neural tube and the descent of my digestive system.
Der Aufstieg meines Neuralrohrs und der Abstieg meines Verdauungssystems.
This is what will create this space here, the integration.
Das ist es, was diesen Raum hier schafft, die Integration.
Here we can clearly see on a section the different tissues, septum transversum,
Hier sehen wir auf einem Schnitt die verschiedenen Gewebe, Septum transversum,
the pleuroperitoneal membranes and also what we call the meso-esophageal
die pleuro-peritonealen Membranen und auch das, was man das Meso
and the paraxial membranes that are there.
-Ösophagus nennt
Not only working on a diaphragm means working on all these spaces
Nicht nur ein Zwerchfell zu bearbeiten, bedeutet, all diese Räume
here.
hier zu bearbeiten.
Often, we work on them here.
Oft bearbeiten wir sie hier.
But in fact, working on a diaphragm is not only freeing all this,
Aber eigentlich bedeutet die Bearbeitung eines Zwerchfells nicht nur die Befreiung all dessen,
these lateral spaces, but also the aorta, the
dieser lateralen Räume, sondern auch der Aorta, der
vena cava and the esophagus,
Vena Cava und des Ösophagus,
and especially the esophageal junction.
und besonders des Ösophagusübergangs.
Because it's a very important area to free up a diaphragm.
Denn das ist eine sehr wichtige Zone, um ein Zwerchfell zu entlasten.
Many patients suffer from...
Viele Patienten leiden an...
esophagitis, peptic disorders
an Ösophagitis, an peptischen Störungen
in the esophagus, enormously.
im Bereich des Ösophagus, enorm.
Well, that blocks your diaphragm.
Nun, das blockiert dein Zwerchfell.
It is absolutely necessary to free and clear
Man muss unbedingt befreien und entlasten
this peri-esophageal space
diesen periösophagealen Raum
with the muscle of Treitz,
mit dem Treitz-Muskel,
the muscle of Anscouver,
dem Anscouver-Muskel,
this small peri-esophageal space
diesen kleinen periösophagealen Raum,
which can even block the entire digestive system
der sogar das gesamte Verdauungssystem blockieren kann,
which is suspended vis-à-vis the carotid foramina,
das gegenüber den Foramina carotica aufgehängt ist,
vis-à-vis the prejugular system,
gegenüber dem präjugulären System,
vis-à-vis of...
gegenüber...
of your anterior, posterior pterygoid attachments,
deinen vorderen, hinteren Pterygoid-Ansätzen,
at the base of the skull, inferior part,
an der Schädelbasis, unterer Teil,
which can create everything here, it's supported.
was hier alles schaffen kann, es wird gestützt.
And so, if you don't have the bell ringing in your head
Und wenn du also nicht gut die Glocke hast, die in deinem Kopf bimmelt,
when it goes down here,
wenn es hier heruntergeht,
you are not free on your symphysis.
bist du nicht frei auf deiner Symphyse.
Because in fact, what happens here?
Denn was passiert hier eigentlich?
You have a magical continuity,
Du hast eine magische Kontinuität,
with a small muscle that is a muscle
mit einem kleinen Muskel, der ein Muskel ist,
which for me is the magician of the system...
der für mich der Magier des Systems ist...
of sphincter opening,
der Öffnung der Schließmuskeln,
of organizing all
der Organisation der gesamten
the functional integrity
funktionellen Integrität
of your primitive vegetative system
deines primitiven vegetativen Systems
and even current
und sogar des aktuellen
in relation to that.
in Bezug darauf.
And what is it called? It continues here.
Und wie heißt das? Es setzt sich hier fort.
Look, it does this
Schau, es macht das
and it continues there. What is that called?
und es setzt sich dort fort. Wie nennen wir das?
The muscle of Treitz.
Der Melkmuskel.
Which contains two types of fibers. Muscle
Der zwei Arten von Fasern enthält. Muskuläre
and non-muscle fibers.
und nicht-muskuläre Fasern.
So two different types of information.
Also zwei verschiedene Arten von Informationen.
it's a muscle that can open
Es ist ein Muskel, der die Luftversorgung
or close the air care
öffnen oder schließen kann.
the falciform ligament, the greater omentum
Das Ligamentum falciforme, das große Omentum
are derived elements
sind abgeleitete Elemente
of the septum transversum
des Septum transversum.
so what can we say?
Was können wir also sagen?
that 1. I have a continuity
Dass ich 1. eine Kontinuität habe,
not only from my mesenchymal
nicht nur von meinen mesenchymalen
cells
Zellen aus,
via the pericardial system
über das perikardiale System
and septum transversum
und das Septum transversum,
but that in addition
sondern dass sich außerdem
from the septum transversum will derive
aus dem Septum transversum
a part of my falciform
ein Teil meines Ligamentum
ligament, and at the same time
falciforme und gleichzeitig
the greater omentum, which are elements
das große Omentum ableiten, die Elemente sind,
that are derived from this transverse septum.
die von diesem Septum transversum abgeleitet sind.
And I remind you that the greater omentum
Und ich erinnere Sie daran, dass das große Omentum
is part of this
Teil dieser
functional integrity of the
funktionellen Integrität des
diaphragm. I am here,
Zwerchfells ist. Ich bin hier,
I have the hiatus of Winslow, and I pass
ich habe den Hiatus von Winslow, und ich gehe
behind the retro-gastric pouch.
hinter den retrogastrischen Beutel.
You see? So I go up
Siehst du? Also gehe ich wieder hoch.
towards the area of the
in den Bereich des
bronchus, I orient my right-left bronchus,
Bronchus, ich richte meinen rot-linken Bronchus aus,
I go towards the spleen, and then I go down again,
ich gehe zur Milz, und dann gehe ich wieder runter,
I pass under the
ich gehe unter dem
above the colon,
über dem Dickdarm,
and I go down again to form
und ich gehe wieder runter, um
a coalescence of four layers
eine Koaleszenz von vier Blättern zu bilden,
to form a greater omentum.
um ein großes Omentum zu bilden.
Lymphatic messenger,
Lymphatischer Bote,
B, T and M, motility,
B, T und M, Motilität,
in relation, all that,
all das in Beziehung
with my diaphragmatic system.
zu meinem Zwerchfell-System.
Another important thing,
Noch etwas Wichtiges,
is this relationship, you see,
das ist diese Beziehung, siehst du,
with what we call the arcuate ligaments.
mit dem, was man die gebogenen Bänder nennt.
You know that, they are here, you see.
Das kennt ihr, die sind hier, siehst du.
It's the arcuate ligament,
Das ist das gebogene Band,
arched ligament,
das Bogenband,
with the psoas arch,
mit dem Psoas-Bogen,
the median arcuate ligament
das mediale Bogenband
with the aortic hiatus.
mit dem Aortenhiatus.
And above, you have an important passage,
Und darüber hast du einen wichtigen Durchgang,
this continuity with the ligament of Treitz.
diese Kontinuität mit dem Ligamentum suspensorium.
But this is interesting
Aber das ist interessant,
because this is an arcuate ligament
weil das ein Bogenband ist
with the quadratus lumborum.
mit dem Musculus quadratus lumborum.
The medial arcuate ligament
Das mediale Bogenband
with the psoas arch.
mit dem Psoas-Bogen.
That means the diaphragm
Das bedeutet, dass das Zwerchfell
continues indirectly
sich indirekt fortsetzt
through my common masses,
durch meine gemeinsamen Massen,
through my quadratus lumborum up to here,
durch meine langen Quadrate bis hierher,
and even up to here vis-à-vis my psoas.
und sogar bis hierher in Bezug auf meinen Psoas.
They are in direct relation with my diaphragm.
Sie stehen in direkter Beziehung zu meinem Zwerchfell.
It's a fascial continuity
Das ist eine fasziale Kontinuität
of diaphragmatic organization.
der Zwerchfellorganisation.
And how can esophagitis disturb
Und wie eine Ösophagitis
even the movement of the knee, for example,
sogar eine Kniebewegung stören kann, zum Beispiel,
by disturbing your mechanics.
indem sie deine Mechanik stört.
Each diaphragm
Jedes Zwerchfell
to conceive it as in
um es als in
relation with the other diaphragms.
Beziehung zu den anderen Zwerchfellen zu betrachten.
Each of the three main diaphragms, cervical, thoracic,
Jedes der drei großen Hauptzwerchfelle, zervikal, thorakal,
pelvic,
pelvisch,
an imbalance of one disturbs the other. Moreover, I find myself in a negative
ein Ungleichgewicht des einen stört das andere. Außerdem befinde ich mich in einem negativen
pressure
Druck
with a positive pressure.
mit positivem Druck.
That is, it is a pressure regulator, so it is a tension regulator,
Das heißt, es ist ein Druckregler, also ist es ein Spannungsregler, also ist es ein hydraulischer
so it is a hydraulic and even thermal regulator.
und sogar thermischer Regler.
You see how this digestive, vascular,
Siehst du, wie dieses Verdauungs-, Gefäß-
lymphatic diaphragm, it's a lymphatic pump?
und Lymphzwerchfell eine Lymphpumpe ist?
How all that vis-à-vis, just of its system, vis-à-vis of the
Wie all das im Verhältnis, allein von seinem System aus, im Verhältnis zur
esophagus, vis-à-vis of the whole system,
Speiseröhre, im Verhältnis zum gesamten System,
cardiac, with its cardiac relation, of all its relation with the phoepatis, and
kardial, mit seiner kardialen Beziehung, seiner gesamten Beziehung zur Phoepatis und
all its relation
seiner gesamten Beziehung
posterior with the greater omentum. And behind, we will find all the
posterior zum großen Omentum. Und dahinter finden wir die gesamte
relation with the quadratus lumborum,
Beziehung zum Quadratus lumborum,
and in addition with the psoas. But
und zusätzlich zu den Psoas. Aber
all that is the same continuity from the heart, from the esophagus,
all das ist eine einzige Kontinuität vom Herzen, von der Speiseröhre,
from the base of the skull, so from the craniosacral axis.
von der Schädelbasis, also von der kraniosakralen Achse.
whether it is the purely notochordal axis or the purely
sei es die rein notochordale Achse oder die rein
Corrings axis.
des Corrings.
The costodiaphragmatic recesses are accumulation sacs for exudates, waste,
Die kostodiaphragmatischen Rezessus sind Säcke zur Ansammlung von Exsudaten, von
both exudates, transpleural and transperitoneal. What does this sentence mean? I have bronchitis, I cough, I point my finger, I have small microbes. I have to eliminate these microbes, after they will not remain complicated. They must be eliminated. They pass. That's why very often, when you have pneumonia afterwards, you have blocked lung bases. It's the same thing if you have gastric problems. If you do something like that, you will eliminate. It accumulates. They need one main thing, it's... space.
Abfall,
it's...
Sie gehen vorbei.
space.
Deshalb ist es sehr oft so,
This is where we see that the human
Hier sehen wir, dass der menschliche Körper
body is a unit at the cellular level, 1, at the tissue level,
eine Einheit auf zellulärer Ebene ist, 1, auf Gewebeebene,
2, and these reactions
2, und diese Abwehr- und Integrationsreaktionen
of defense and integration can occur at any level.
auf jeder Ebene stattfinden können.
Why? Because
Warum? Weil
there is a tissue continuity of the splanchnopleure and the somatopleure. This
es eine Gewebekontinuität der Splanchnopleura und der Somatopleura gibt. Das
is
ist
what we just saw with the diaphragm.
es, was wir gerade mit dem Zwerchfell gesehen haben.